Woman. Warrior. Queen.
Elizabeth: The Golden Age is a drama, history,
romance film directed by Shekhar Kapur.
When Queen Elizabeth's reign is threatened by ruthless familial betrayal and Spain's invading
army, she and her shrewd adviser must act to safeguard the lives of her people.
Elizabeth I, Queen of England, played by Cate Blanchett.
Sir Christopher Hatton, played by Laurence Fox.
Sir Walter Raleigh, played by Clive Owen.
Sir Francis Walsingham, played by Geoffrey Rush.
Amyas Paulet, played by Tom Hollander.
Elizabeth Throckmorton, played by Abbie Cornish.
Elizabeth: The Golden Age is a 2007 biographical historical drama film directed by
Shekhar Kapur and produced by Universal Pictures and Working Title Films.
It stars Cate Blanchett in the title role and is a loose but fact-based portrayal of events during the
latter part of the reign of Elizabeth I, forming a sequel to Kapur's 1998 film Elizabeth.
The film co-stars Geoffrey Rush (reprising his role from the previous film),
Clive Owen, Jordi Mollà, Abbie Cornish, and Samantha Morton.
The screenplay was written by William Nicholson and Michael Hirst,
and the score composed by Craig Armstrong and A.
Guy Hendrix Dyas was the film's production designer and co-visual effects
supervisor, and the costumes were created by Alexandra Byrne.
The film was shot at Shepperton Studios and locations around the United Kingdom.
The film premiered on 9 September 2007 at the
Toronto International Film Festival.
It opened in wide release in the United States on 12 October 2007, premiered in London on 23 October 2007,
and opened wide on 2 November 2007 throughout the rest of the UK and Republic of Ireland.
At the 80th Academy Awards, the film won Best Costume Design and
Blanchett received a nomination for Best Actress.
The film explores themes of assassination, england,
queen elizabeth i, religious war, tudor.
The tone is emotional.